

CURRICULUM VITAE

#### **Details**

Shipton Bellinger United Kingdom +44 7821 972 567 micael.lazaro@gmail.com

#### Links

LinkedIn

#### **Profile**

#### From OT to IT

In 2023, I started the course in Full Stack Development with the reputable and well recognized Code Institute and I am looking to change my career to IT.

I am an Occupational Therapist Assistant (healthcare sector), I started my working experience in this field 3 years ago. I worked as a product specialist and sales representative in a few companies in the UK where I learned in depth about mobility and postural equipment and their different specifications.

In 2017 I also set up my own company LAZAREHAB LTD which is an exclusive distributor in the UK for Hernik Postural Car Seats specially designed for children with disabilities.

www.lazarehab.com

# **Employment History**

#### Co Director, Lazarehab

NOVEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

Responsible for increasing sales

- Introducing the company on the market
- Demonstrating product
- Supporting Physiotherapists, Occupational Therapist (Prescribers) and Rehabilitation Engineers on pediatric clinics by doing:
- Assessments preparing demo equipment for the clinics to make sure the right product is prescribed regarding the client's needs;
- Handover Making the final adjustments on the product to be suitable to the client;
- Reviews and technical support Considering the client may have some changes in his clinical condition, it's essential to make sure the product is still providing proper support according to that
- Explaining the main features of the products to parents and all the reasonable procedures so their children can achieve the best posture
- Managing diary
- Contacting customers to book appointments by telephone /email/ video call
- Increasing database contacts
- Contacting charities regarding funding
- Contacting and negotiating with dealers
- Sending quotations
- Supporting Lazarehab at national and local exhibitions (PMG, Naidex, Kidz exhibitions...

# Occupational Therapist Assistant , AJM (Wheelchair Services) , London and Portsmouth

MAY 2020 - MARCH 2023

Key Responsibilities: - Managing diary

- Booking assessments, reviews, and handovers at the clinic at the wheelchair service and in the community.
- Assessing the Service User in order to understand if meets the criteria for wheelchair provision (manual wheelchair, powered wheelchair or Tilt-in-space wheelchair...)
- Adapt the environment to suit the service user's needs by recommending and ordering appropriate and cost-effective equipment.
- Reviewing the client's posture in the current manual wheelchair/buggy/powered chair.
- Adjusting/replacing parts or accessories of the current wheelchair.
- Skilled in how to take the correct measurements of the Service User
- Environment assessment and accessibility in order to provide the right equipment.
- Delivering and adjusting the wheelchair so it could meet the client's clinical needs in order to be discharged from the Hospital.
- Gathering and uploading information on the system and ordering the wheelchairs and accessories on BEST and ELMS.
- Making all kinds of handovers with products from Sunrise Medical, Invacare, RMS, SOS, fitting belts, harnesses, trays...

# $Health care\ assistant, First\ city\ Home\ Community\ Health care, Swindon$

OCTOBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

Making regular visits to the elderly and people with special needs, assisting them on a daily basis.

- Serving meals and helping to feed patients.
- Helping people to move around and taking them to medical appointments
- Assisting with personal care and toileting.
- Talking to patients and making them comfortable.
- Monitoring patients' conditions by taking temperatures, pulse, respiration and weight.
- Checking regularly their equipment (wheelchair, hoist, zimmer frame,

#### Healthcare assistant, Cheriton Nursing Home Healthcare, Swindon

JANUARY 2018 - OCTOBER 2019

- Moving and handling safely patients with the following equipment:
- Ceiling hoists;
- Mobile hoists;
- Standing aids;
- Transfer boards;
- Turn tables:

- Slings.
- Changing the position of patients in bed 2 in 2 hours with the help of a sliding sheet.
- Looking after patient's posture on their wheelchairs and comfort lift chairs.
- Hygiene supporting patients with the following equipment:
- Mobile shower commodes with and without tilt in space;
- Adjustable height baths;
- Bath hoists or bath lifts.
- Toileting supporting patients with the following equipment:
- Commode chairs;
- Seat raisers for the toilet.
- Personal development Health & Safety;
- Infection control;
- First Aid;
- Giving care advice;
- Personal care;
- Healthcare;
- Supervising;

### Area Sales Manager, rehabilitation manufacturing services (RMS), Kent

OCTOBER 2016 - JANUARY 2018

Assessments and demonstrations of mobility and postural products for people with disabilities at wheelchair services, schools and home visits.

Manufacturer of:

Powered Wheelchair Buggy

**Seating Systems** 

Headrests

**Belts Harness Accessories** 

Brands represented in exclusivity by RMS:

- Ormesa <a href="http://www.ormesa.com/en/">http://www.ormesa.com/en/</a>
- Eurovema <a href="http://www.eurovema.se/default.asp?sLang=en-gb">http://www.eurovema.se/default.asp?sLang=en-gb</a>
- Comfort Company <a href="http://www.comfortcompany.com">http://www.comfortcompany.com</a>
- Dynamic NXT Seating Series <a href="http://www.dynamichcs.com/index.php/en/">http://www.dynamichcs.com/index.php/en/</a>
- Seating Matrix Heads First <a href="http://www.matrixseating.com/Heads-First-">http://www.matrixseating.com/Heads-First-</a>

Other brands represented (non-exclusivity)

- Convaid <a href="http://www.convaid.com/">http://www.convaid.com/</a>
- Otto Bock http://www.ottobock.co.uk/
- Sunrise Medical <a href="http://www.sunrisemedical.co.uk/">http://www.sunrisemedical.co.uk/</a>
- Invacare http://www.invacare.co.uk/ www.ineedawheelchair.co.uk

### Area Sales Manager, Etac (R82), East Anglia

- Responsible to increase sales at East Anglia - Introducing the company on market - Demonstrating product - Doing assessments with Occupational Therapist - Managing diary - Contacting customers to book appointments by telephone /email - Increasing database contacts - Contacting and negotiating with dealers - Supporting R82 at national and local exhibitions (PMG, Naidex, Kidz exhibitions...) Healthcare assistant, Tunbridge Wells Care Healthcare, Kent MAY 2014 - MAY 2016 - Supportive care - Moving and handling safely patients with the following equipment: - Ceiling hoists; - Mobile hoists; - Standing aids; - Transfer boards; - Turn tables; - Slings. - Changing the position of patients in bed 2 in 2 hours with the help of a sliding sheet. - Looking after patient's posture on their wheelchairs and comfort lift chairs. - Hygiene - supporting patients with the following equipment: - Mobile shower commodes with and without tilt in space; - Adjustable height baths; - Bath hoists or bath lifts.
  - Toileting supporting patients with the following equipment:
  - Commode chairs;
  - Seat raisers for the toilet.
  - Personal development Health & Safety;
  - Infection control;
  - First Aid;
  - Giving care advice;
  - Personal care;
  - Healthcare;
  - Supervising;

## **Education**

# Full Stack Software Development Diploma, Code Institute/Peterborough University, Remote

MARCH 2023 - PRESENT

# NVQ level 2 in health and social care, College, Kent

MAY 2015

# Care certificate, College, Kent

MAY 2015

# Dementia Care training courses, College, Kent

MAY 2015